Finding Aid for the Terrence O'Flaherty Papers PASC.0026
UCLA Library Special Collections
Terrence O'Flaherty papers
circa 1940s-circa1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
O'Flaherty, Terrence
PASC.0026
135.0 linear feet (332 boxes)
24 linear feet (14 unprocessed record cartons, 10 unprocessed flat boxes)
3 audiovisual carriers (2 audiocassettes, 1 record)
Terrence O'Flaherty worked as television critic for the San Francisco Chronicle from 1952-1986. The bulk of the collection consists of television stills and promotional material collected by O'Flaherty during the course of his 37-year journalistic career. Additionally included are scrapbooks documenting his newspaper columns, subject files containing research materials, and a small amount of correspondence and other writings by O'Flaherty.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audio materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed audio materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Terrence O'Flaherty, 1986. Addition to the collection gift of Lynn Hickerson, 2007.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9925510713606533
Biography/History
Terrence O'Flaherty was born in Iowa in 1917, and raised in Los Angeles. He graduated with a BA from the University of California, Berkeley, and went on to work as a fact checker at Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer. He served as a communications officer in the US Navy during World War II. His first newspaper position was with the Santa Monica Independent, in 1949, and in 1950, he began working for the San Francisco Chronicle, where he would remain until his retirement in 1986.
O'Flaherty was one of the first commentators to write seriously about the then-emerging medium of television. In addition to writing his widely read television column for the San Francisco Chronicle, O'Flaherty was involved with a number of other television-related activities. From 1952 to 1984, he was a member of the board of the Peabody Awards; and in 1961 and 1962, he hosted PM West, a nightly news show, broadcast from San Francisco.
In 1974, O'Flaherty was nominated for the Pulitzer Prize, and in 1988, was presented with an Emmy Award. In 1995, he published the book Masterpiece Theatre, a retrospective look at the PBS series of the same name. Terrence O'Flaherty died of pancreatic cancer in 2001, at the age of 83.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of material related to television critic and newspaper columnist, Terrence O'Flaherty. The bulk of the collection is television stills and promotional material that O'Flaherty collected over the course of his 37-year career. The stills date from approximately 1952-1990, and document television programs from all of the major networks. The promotional material includes press kits from television programs and networks, as well as print advertisements, invitations, and other promotional items sent to O'Flaherty. Also included are scrapbooks of his many newspaper columns.
Also included in the collection is a small amount of cards, notes, and column reader letters; subject files which appear to have been assembled by O'Flaherty on a range of television-related themes; television scripts and recordings sent to O'Flaherty to promote television programing; and a small quantity of O'Flaherty's writings. Additionally, there publications covering the history, development, economics, sociology and technology of television. Some of the book publications are signed or contain personal notes to O'Flaherty and may contain additional news release or promotional material in the item.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Scrapbooks
Subject files
Writings
Oral history
Correspondence
Stills
Promotional material
Publications
Sound recordings
Related Material
Morrie Gelman Papers (Collection 292). Available at Library Special Collections, Young Research Library, UCLA.
Television; Journalists -- Archives; O'Flaherty, Terrence -- Archives; O'Flaherty, Terrence
- Scrapbooks, mid-1940s-mid 1980s, bulk 1960s-1970s; 1960-1979
  Organization and Arrangement
  The scrapbooks are arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Content
  The majority of the scrapbooks document O'Flaherty's career as a newspaper columnist. They consist of clippings of O'Flaherty's writings for newspapers including the San Francisco Chronicle and the Santa Monica Independent. Some of the scrapbooks also include reader mail responses to O'Flaherty's columns. A small number of books contain other clippings and television publicity photographs. Additionally there is a scrapbook presented to O'Flaherty on the television program This Is Your Life in 1954.
  - Wartime ads from Life magazine, (1944 June 26) (Box 327, Folder 2)
  - Feature Articles Santa Monica Independent, (1949 Jan - 1949 July) (Box 295)
  - Early Books Volume A, (1950 Feb 12 - 1950 May 16) (Box 295)
  - Volume 1, (1953 Feb 16 - 1954 June 11) (Box 278)
  - Volume 2, (1954 June 14 - 1955 Oct 12) (Box 278)
    Scope and Contents note
    With ink drawing inscribed to O'Flaherty, originally found loose among other papers.
  - Volume 3, (1955 Oct 13 - 1956 Nov 11) (Box 279)
  - Volume 4, (1956 Nov 12 - 1957 Oct 20) (Box 279)
  - Volume 5, (1957 Oct 21 - 1958 Nov 16) (Box 280)
  - Volume 6, (1958 Nov 17 - 1959 Dec 2) (Box 280)
  - Volume 7, (1959 Dec 3 - 1960 Oct 31) (Box 281)
  - Volume 8, (1960 Nov 1 - 1961 Sep 24) (Box 281)
  - Volume 9, (1961 Sep 25 - 1962 Nov 30) (Box 282)
  - Volume 10, (1962 Dec 3 - 1963 Dec 31) (Box 282)
  - Volume 11, (1964 Jan 1 - 1964 Dec 31) (Box 283)
  - Volume 12, (1965 Jan 1 - 1965 Dec 31) (Box 283)
  - Volume 13, (1966 Jan 1 - 1966 Dec 31) (Box 284)
  - Volume 14, (1967 Jan 2 - 1967 Dec 30) (Box 284)
  - Volume 15, (1968 Jan 1 - 1968 Dec 31) (Box 285)
  - Volume 16, (1969 Jan 1 - 1969 Dec 31) (Box 285)
    With folder of letters labeled Agnew speech - reader reaction to O'F column Nov 15 1969.
  - Volume 17, (1970 Jan 1 - 1970 Dec 31) (Box 286)
  - Volume 18, (1971 Jan 1 - 1971 Dec 31) (Box 286)
  - Volume 19, (1972 Jan 1 - 1972 Dec 30) (Box 287)
  - Publicity photographs from 1973 Emmy Awards (Box 287)
    From volume 20.
  - Volume 20, (1973 Jan 1 - 1973 Dec 8) (Box 287)
  - Volume 21, (1974 Jan 7 - 1974 Dec 31) (Box 288)
  - Volume 22, (1975 Jan 1 - 1975 Dec 31) (Box 288)
  - Volume 23, (1976 Jan 1 - 1976 Dec 31) (Box 289)
    With folder of letters and photos labeled 1976 scrapbook items
  - Television publicity photos, (1977) (Box 289)
    From volume 24.
  - Volume 24, (1977 Jan 1 - 1977 Dec 31) (Box 289)
  - Scrapbook '77, (1977-78) (Box 306, Folder 10)
    Correspondence and reader mail.
  - Volume 25, (1978 Jan 2 - 1978 Dec 9) (Box 290)
  - Scrapbook '79, (1979) (Box 306, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, press releases, reader mail, stills.
  - Volume 26, (1979 Jan 1 - 1979 Dec 22) (Box 290)
  - 1980 Scrapbook (Box 306, Folder 12)
    Clippings, correspondence, press releases, reader mail, stills, and other printed material.
  - Volume 27, (1980 Jan 21 - 1980 Dec 15) (Box 291)
  - 1981 Scrapbook (Box 307, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook '81, (1981) (Box 307, Folder 1)
    Clippings, correspondence, press releases, reader mail, stills, postcards from Phyllis Diller, and other print material.
  - Volume 28, (1981 Jan 21 - 1981 Dec 31) (Box 291)
  - Volume 29, (1982 Jan 1 - 1982 Dec 30) (Box 292)
  - Volume 30, (1983 Jan 3 - 1983 Dec 30) (Box 292)
  - Volume 31, (1984 Jan 1 - 1984 Dec 30) (Box 293)
  - 1985 Scrapbook material (Box 307, Folder 3)
  - Volume 32, (1985 Jan 1 - 1985 Dec 2) (Box 293)
  - Supplement to '86 book reader reaction to Arab-Isreal columns, (1986) (Box 307, Folder 4)
    Reader letters in response to O'Flaherty's columns about the conflict between Israel and Palestine.
  - Volume 33, (1986 Jan 7 - 1986 May 2) (Box 294)
    With folder labeled duplicate clippings 1986
  - This is Your Life, (c. 1954) (Box 327, Folder 1)
- Subject files, 1950s-1980s
  The files in the series are arranged alphabetically by name or subject titles.
  The series consists of subject files that appear to have been compiled and utilized by O'Flaherty over the course of his writing career by. They contain research material such as clippings, photographs, and notes on a variety of topics. The bulk of the files document performers and media personalities, including Julie Andrews, Pearl Bailey, Tallulah Bankhead, Noel Coward, Bette Davis, Ethel Merman, Elvis Presley, O.J. Simpson, Gore Vidal, Lawrence Welk, and among others. Also included are files about events, such as the Academy Awards, and files containing a small amount of television and motion picture stills.
  - Unidentified stills and slides, (undated) (Box 324, Folder 6)
  - 28 Julius First Chronicle Story, (1953) (Box 307, Folder 15)
    Appear to be floor plans of O'Flaherty's home for article about interior design.
  - ABC - Great Ideas (The), (undated) (Box 324, Folder 8)
  - Academy Awards (folder 1 of 2), (ca. 1960s-1970s) (Box 304, Folder 3)
    Press releases, stills, and clippings
  - Academy Awards (folder 2 of 2), (ca. 1960s-1970s) (Box 304, Folder 4)
    Clippings, copies of Variety, The Hollywood Reporter, and Motion Picture Daily
  - Academy Awards 1979 Oscar Annual (Box 304, Folder 2)
  - Alexander, Ben, (1959) (Box 314, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Judith, (ca. 1960-1980) (Box 314, Folder 3)
  - Andrews, Julie, (1972 July 7) (Box 314, Folder 4)
  - Angelou, Maya, (undated) (Box 314, Folder 5)
  - Ann-Margaret, (ca. 1968) (Box 314, Folder 2)
  - Bailey, Pearl, (undated) (Box 314, Folder 6)
  - Ball, Lucille - TV Guide O'Flaherty cover story, (1974 July 6) (Box 314, Folder 8)
  - Ball, Lucille 1911-1989, (ca. 1950-1980) (Box 314, Folder 7)
    With photo inscribed by Desi Arnaz.
  - Ballard, Kaye, (ca. 1950-1990) (Box 314, Folder 9)
  - Bankhead, Tallulah, (ca. 1960) (Box 314, Folder 10)
  - Bankhead, Tallulah, (ca. 1980) (Box 314, Folder 11)
  - Baxter, Dr. Frank April '64 England Shakespeare, (1964) (Box 314, Folder 12)
  - Beatles, The, (1964) (Box 314, Folder 13)
  - Beebe, Lucius, (ca. 1950-1980) (Box 314, Folder 14)
  - Benny, Jack, (1958, 1977) (Box 314, Folder 15)
  - Buckley, Wm. F., (ca. 1970) (Box 314, Folder 17)
  - Buckley-Vidal feud, (1968) (Box 314, Folder 16)
  - Burr, Raymond, (ca. 1968) (Box 314, Folder 18)
  - Burton, Richard, (undated) (Box 314, Folder 19)
  - Capote, Truman, (ca. 1970) (Box 314, Folder 20)
  - Carlisle, Kitty, (1958 March 20) (Box 314, Folder 21)
  - Carroll, Madeleine, (1958) (Box 314, Folder 22)
  - Carson, Johnny, (1955, 1982) (Box 314, Folder 23)
  - Channing, Carol, (ca. 1960-1980) (Box 314, Folder 24)
    Includes Christmas cards. See Box 314 for more.
  - Chaplin, Charlie, (ca. 1960) (Box 314, Folder 25)
  - Cherry Sisters, (1970) (Box 314, Folder 26)
  - Chevalier, Maurice, (ca. 1960) (Box 314, Folder 27)
  - Child, Julia, (ca. 1960-1970) (Box 314, Folder 28)
  - Churchill, Wintston, (ca. 1960) (Box 314, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, (ca. 1950s-1980s) (Box 307, Folder 11)
  - Colbert, Claudette, (1963-1964) (Box 314, Folder 30)
  - Columbo, Russ, (undated) (Box 314, Folder 31)
  - Cousteau, Jacques and Philippe, (ca. 1970) (Box 314, Folder 32)
  - Coward, Noel, (ca. 1950-1970) (Box 314, Folder 33)
  - Cromwell, Richard, (c. 1946) (Box 314, Folder 35)
  - Crosby, Bing, (ca. 1970) (Box 314, Folder 34)
  - Cukor, George, (ca. 1970) (Box 314, Folder 36)
  - Danilova, Alexandra, (ca. 1970-1980) (Box 315, Folder 1)
  - Davies, Marian, (undated) (Box 315, Folder 2)
  - Davis, Bette, (1963, 1977) (Box 315, Folder 3)
  - De Wolfe, Elsie (Lady Mendl), (undated) (Box 315, Folder 5)
  - Dean, James, (ca. 1950-1980) (Box 315, Folder 4)
  - Diller, Phillys, (ca. 1950-1980) (Box 315, Folder 6)
  - Dooley, Tom, (ca. 1959) (Box 315, Folder 7)
  - Drag, (ca. 1960-1980) (Box 324, Folder 10)
    Stills and headshots of various male performers in drag.
  - Dunaway, Faye, (1981) (Box 315, Folder 8)
  - Ferry, Tony, (ca. 1940) (Box 315, Folder 9)
  - Fisher, M.F.K., (1981, 1983) (Box 315, Folder 10)
  - Fonda, Henry, (ca. 1971) (Box 315, Folder 11)
  - Gable, Clark, (1970) (Box 315, Folder 12)
  - Garbo, Greta, (ca. 1970-1990) (Box 315, Folder 13)
  - Garson, Greer, (1974) (Box 315, Folder 14)
  - Graber, Ted, (ca. 1980-1990) (Box 315, Folder 15)
  - Graham, Sheilah, (1965) (Box 315, Folder 16)
  - Grant, Cary, (undated) (Box 315, Folder 17)
  - Haines, William, (ca. 1998) (Box 308, Folder 3)
  - Halliburton, Richard, (undated) (Box 308, Folder 5)
  - Hallmark Hall of Fame, (1991 June 28) (Box 308, Folder 4)
    Program from 40th Anniversary Event hosted by UCLA Film and Television Archive
  - Hauser, Gayelord, (undated) (Box 308, Folder 6)
  - Hayes, Helen, (undated) (Box 308, Folder 7)
  - Hepburn, Katharine, (undated) (Box 308, Folder 8)
  - Heston, Charlton, (undated) (Box 308, Folder 9)
    Empty.
  - Home remodeling projects (Box 312)
    7 folders.
  - Hopper, Hedda, (ca. 1950-1970) (Box 308, Folder 11)
  - Hopper's Hollywood, (ca. 1960) (Box 305, Folder 5)
  - H-Performers, (ca. 1956-1986) (Box 324, Folder 7)
    Stills and headshots of various male performers.
  - H-Photos - TV Stills, (ca. 1950-1980) (Box 324, Folder 9)
    Stills and headshots of various male performers. Folder labeled see also: Beefcake Box
  - Hunter, Tab, (ca. 1950-1960) (Box 308, Folder 12)
  - Ince, Thomas, (undated) (Box 308, Folder 13)
  - Isherwood, Christopher, (ca. 1970-1980) (Box 308, Folder 14)
    Adult material?
  - Jolson, Al, (undated) (Box 308, Folder 15)
  - Judy Garland, (ca. 1960s) (Box 324, Folder 11)
  - Julius Street/Fred Lyon - "Living for Young Homemakers", (1965 May 18) (Box 307, Folder 16)
    Correspondence, photographs, and floor plan. Appear to be of O'Flaherty's home.
  - Junkets - with Bob Hope, (1956, 1957) (Box 308, Folder 10)
  - Lanza, Mario, (ca. 1950) (Box 308, Folder 16)
  - Lee, Gypsy Rose, (ca. 1950-1960) (Box 308, Folder 17)
  - Liberace, (ca. 1950-1970) (Box 308, Folder 18)
  - Loud Family, (ca. 1970) (Box 308, Folder 19)
  - Lunt, Alfred and Lynn Fontanne, (ca. 1950-1960) (Box 308, Folder 20)
  - Lynde, Paul, (ca. 1980) (Box 308, Folder 21)
  - Maclaine, Shirley, (1975 Apr 16) (Box 308, Folder 22)
  - Maharis, George, (1966) (Box 308, Folder 23)
  - Mansfield, Jayne, (1980) (Box 308, Folder 24)
  - Martin, Mary, (ca. 1970-1980) (Box 308, Folder 25)
  - Mason, James, (ca. 1950) (Box 308, Folder 26)
  - Mathis, Johnny, (ca. 1960-1990) (Box 308, Folder 27)
  - Maugham, Somerset, (ca. 1950-1970) (Box 308, Folder 28)
  - Mayer, Louis B., (1974 May 29) (Box 308, Folder 29)
  - McPherson, Aimee Semple, (ca. 1976) (Box 308, Folder 30)
  - Merman, Ethel, (1969 Nov 24) (Box 308, Folder 31)
  - Meyer, Baron Adolf de, (ca. 1970) (Box 308, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous (various television stills), (ca. 1964) (Box 324, Folder 2)
  - Miss America, (ca. 1960-1970) (Box 308, Folder 33)
  - Monroe, Marilyn, (1955) (Box 309, Folder 1)
  - Moran, Lois, (1959, 1961) (Box 309, Folder 2)
  - Morley, Robert, (1992) (Box 309, Folder 3)
  - Motion Picture Stills 1, (undated) (Box 324, Folder 12)
    Includes stills from Ben Hur, Mrs. Miniver, Mutiny on the Bounty, Pal Joey, Quest for Fire, Witness for the Prosecution, and others.
  - Motion Picture Stills 2, (undated) (Box 325, Folder 1)
    Includes stills from 39 Steps (The), Black Pirate (The), Joan of Arc, Prisoner of Zenda, Wizard of Oz (The), and others.
  - Motion Picture Stills 3, (undated) (Box 325, Folder 2)
    Includes stills from Dark Angel (The), Gorgeous Hussy, Ocean's Eleven, Paths of Glory, Robe (The), Rome Adventure, Singin' in the Rain, Vertigo, and others.
  - Motion Picture Stills 4, (undated) (Box 325, Folder 4)
    Includes stills from Citizen Cane, Dodge City, King Kong, Maltese Falcon (The), Pennies from Heaven, Rebecca of Sunnybrook Farm, Thin Man (The), and others.
  - Motion Picture Stills 5, (undated) (Box 325, Folder 5)
    Includes stills from 2001: A Space Odyssey, Dinner at Eight, Farewell to Arms (A), Gypsy, Ivanhoe, National Velvet, Postman Always Rings Twice (The), Ten Commandments (The), and others.
  - Motion Picture Stills 6, (undated) (Box 325, Folder 6)
    Includes stills from Frankenstein Meets the Wolfman, Potemkin, Rally Round the Flag, Seven Year Itch (The), Wild One (The), and others.
  - Movie stars first TV roles, (ca. 1950-1960) (Box 325, Folder 7)
    Stills and photographs of film stars including Fred Astaire, Joan Crawford, Lillian Gish, Alec Guiness, Betty Grable, Mickey Rooney, Ann Sheridan, Shirley Temple, and others making television apperances.
  - Murray, Arthur, (1958 Oct) (Box 309, Folder 4)
  - Murrow, Edward R., (undated) (Box 309, Folder 5)
  - O'F Photos Celebrities, (undated) (Box 324, Folder 3)
    O'Flaherty with Maya Angelou, Jerry Colonna, Maureen O'Hara, Fess Parker, and others; signed photos of Nannette Fabray and Jan Merlin; and other celebrity photographs.
  - O'F Photos PM West, ([1961-1962]) (Box 324, Folder 4)
    Stills from PM West, a late-night talk show hosted by O'Flaherty.
  - O'Flaherty on Lineup, (undated) (Box 325, Folder 3)
    Clippings and photos pertaining to O'Flaherty's guest appearance on The Lineup.
  - O'Flaherty, Liam, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 6)
  - O'Hair, Madalyn Murray, (ca. 1960-2000) (Box 309, Folder 7)
  - Olivier, Laurence, (1972) (Box 309, Folder 8)
  - Peabody Radio and Television Awards (The) digest of 1966 entries, (ca. 1966) (Box 306, Folder 7)
  - Pegler, Westbrook, (1940-[1990]) (Box 309, Folder 9)
  - Presley, Elvis, (ca. 1950-1990) (Box 309, Folder 10)
  - Radio, (undated) (Box 325, Folder 8)
  - Radio - magazines, (1923, 1941, 1943) (Box 326, Folder 1)
  - Radio - NBC 1926-51, (1951, 1956) (Box 326, Folder 3)
    Includes The NBC Story 25th and 30th anniversary press releases.
  - Rambo, Dirk and Dack, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 11)
  - Ray, Johnnie, (ca. 1950-1990) (Box 309, Folder 12)
    Restricted? Adult?
  - Reardon, John, (ca. 1960) (Box 309, Folder 13)
  - Reeves, Steve, (ca. 1950) (Box 309, Folder 14)
  - Reinhardt, Max, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 15)
  - Renaldo, Tito, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 16)
  - Reuter, Hans, (1939) (Box 309, Folder 17)
  - Rooney, Andrew, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 18)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, (ca. 1950-1970) (Box 309, Folder 19)
  - Rudie, Evelyn, (ca. 1950-1970) (Box 309, Folder 20)
  - Sahl, Mort, (1954, 1960) (Box 309, Folder 29)
  - Shakespeare on TV, (ca. 1950-1980) (Box 309, Folder 22)
  - Shakespeare, Wm., (ca. 1960-1990) (Box 309, Folder 21)
  - Sheen, Fulton, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 23)
  - Shore, Dinah, (ca. 1950-1990) (Box 309, Folder 24)
  - Sillman, Leonard, (ca. 1952) (Box 309, Folder 25)
    Program for New Faces of 1952.
  - Simpson, O.J., (ca. 1970) (Box 309, Folder 26)
  - Sinatra, Frank, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 27)
  - Stanford, Sally, (1978) (Box 309, Folder 28)
  - Streisand, Barbra, (ca. 1960) (Box 309, Folder 30)
  - Sylvania Television Awards programs and press releases, (1954-1957) (Box 306, Folder 8)
  - Taylor, Elizabeth, (ca.1970-1980) (Box 309, Folder 31)
  - Temple, Shirley, (ca. 1950) (Box 309, Folder 32)
  - Thomas, Lowell, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 33)
  - Thurn und Taxis, Johann, (ca. 1990) (Box 309, Folder 34)
  - To be filed, (c. 1960s-1980s) (Box 307, Folder 17)
    Clippings, correspondence, press kits, and reader mail.
  - Tomlin, Lily, (ca. 1970) (Box 309, Folder 35)
  - Turner, Lana, (1995) (Box 309, Folder 36)
  - TV - Special editions, (1953, 1956, 1966, 1967) (Box 326, Folder 4)
    Clippings and copies of television-related magazines.
  - Umberto II, King of Italy Count de Sarre, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 37)
  - Upstairs Downstairs, (undated) (Box 309, Folder 38)
    Press kit.
  - Valentino, Rudolph, (undated) (Box 310, Folder 1)
  - Vampira, (1954) (Box 310, Folder 2)
  - Van Doren, Charles, (ca. 1950) (Box 310, Folder 3)
  - Vidal, Gore, (ca. 1950-1990) (Box 310, Folder 4)
  - Webb, Clifton, (undated) (Box 310, Folder 5)
  - Welk, Lawrence, (ca. 1950-1990) (Box 310, Folder 6)
  - Westerns 3, (ca. 1950-1970) (Box 324, Folder 5)
    Stills from A Man Called Shenandoah, Maverick, The Texan, Wagon Train, and other television Westerns.
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd, (1963, 1985) (Box 310, Folder 7)
  - Yeon, John, (undated) (Box 310, Folder 8)
- Writings, undated, 1956, 1990
  The series comprised a small amount of written work by O'Flaherty, both in published and draft, typescript form. Also included is one folder of written work by other authors.
  There is no specific arrangment to the series.
  - Annual of the George Foster Peabody Broadcasting Awards with article by O'Flaherty, (1990) (Box 315, Folder 18)
  - Columns to accompany PIBX collection, (undated) (Box 299, Folder 5)
  - Salute to Marlene Dietrich, (undated) (Box 305, Folder 4)
    Booklet with column by O'Flaherty
  - San Francisco Chronicle TV World, (1956 May 20) (Box 306, Folder 2)
    With front page column by O'Flaherty
  - Typescript page and envelope addressed to Landis Everson, (undated) (Box 332, Folder 17)
  - Typescript pages, (undated) (Box 306, Folder 9)
    Appears to be draft for O'Flaherty's column.
  - Writings by O'Flaherty, (undated) (Box 310, Folder 9)
  - Writings by others, (undated) (Box 310, Folder 10)
- Oral history
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  SERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  - Carey McWilliams oral history (3 folders), undated (Box 313)
  - O'Flaherty oral history material (12 folders), undated (Box 311)
    12 folders.
  - O'Flaherty oral history material (18 folders), undated (Box 312)
  - Oral history - 16 audio cassette tapes, (ca. 1989) (Box 313)
    RESTRICTED: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    6 tapes with sides labeled 1-9; 3 tapes labeled June 13 1989; 1 tape each labeled 21 Feb 89, May 24 1989, 27 June 1989, Test Tape, and The Making of an Oral History; two unidentified tapes; and handwritten notes. From box marked Clow Oral History Tapes.
- Correspondence, 1950s-2000
  The bulk of the series are cards and notes sent to O'Flaherty by friends, family, businesses, and personalities. Among the individuals are Perry Como, Bing Crosby, Carol Channing, Phyllis Diller, Jackie Gleason, Merv Griffin, Rock Hudson, Bob Hope, Gladys Knight and the Pips, Liberace, Ronald and Nancy Reagan, William Shatner, Red Skelton, Barbara Stanwyck, Danny Thomas, Marlo Thomas, Lawrence Welk, Adam West, Robert Young, and other notable public figures. Networks and studios represented include ABC, CBS, HBO, NBC, and Walt Disney, and local broadcasters such as KPIX-5, KRON-TV and KQED. There is also a small amount of correspondence that is primarily reader mail, and a program and correspondence related to the 1953 San Francisco's Hundred Leaders of Tomorrow event, where O'Flaherty was honored.
  The files are arranged in loose chronological order.
  - Cards A-J, (ca. 1960-1980) (Box 316)
    From Ed Asner, Willie L. Brown, Mitzi (Gaynor) Bean, Perry Como, Bing Crosby, Carol Channing, Phillys Diller, Jackie Gleason, Merv Griffin, Rock Hudson, Bob Hope, and others.
  - Cards K-S, (ca. 1960-1980) (Box 317)